

## **Sotaro Yoshimoto**

Senior Frontend Developer

Hirosaki-Shi, Japan +1 559 588 4242 · <u>sotaro.yoshimoto@gmail.com</u>

Skills HTML		
CSS		
JavaScript		
Bootstrap		
Tailwind CS	S	
Angular		
React		
Redux		
Typescript		
Web3.js		
PHP		
Laravel		
C#		
Python		
Node		
Jest		
Mocha		
Git		

#### **Hobbies**

Football, Swimming, Dancing, Song

#### **Profile**

Hello. I am *Sotaro Yoshimoto* from *Japan*. I am a Front End Developer with *6+ years* experience in freelancer world, Specialist in building websites using *React js*, and I use React js to *keep up* with the latest trends to ensure quality work. My work experience in the tech and startup industries has helped me to be careful in carrying out any task. That's why I'm used to working remotely with *minimal supervision* but with *maximum results*. I am an expert in creating and developing the front view of a website. I feel *comfortable* meeting new people and love the challenge of learning something new and developing my skills.

I am easy to communicate with, tech savvy and hardworking. I don't shy away from responsibilities and I believe that I am the right person for the job

## **Employment History**

Web Developer, Bang Team

February 2016 — December 2018

- Developed themes and plugins on WordPress.
- Reworked completely a magazine site using the framework *Laravel*.
- Integrated Google Maps for displaying event locations.
- Built a basic mobile application written in *React Native*.

#### Senior React Developer, CODE2B, Košice, Slovakia

December 2018 — December 2019

- Maintained *energy and enthusiasm* in fast-paced environment.
- Actively listened to customers, handled concerns quickly and escalated major issues to supervisor.
- Demonstrated respect, friendliness and willingness to help wherever needed.
- Developed and implemented *performance improvement* strategies and plans to promote continuous improvement.
- Employed a variety of languages such as *HTML*, *CSS*, *JavaScript*, *bootstrap*, *jQuery and react* to write & create user-friendly web pages.
- Improve on the brand consistency throughout the design and maintained & improved the company's website by adding more features and functionality.
- Developed the latest required user features using React library and built reusable components & front-end libraries for future use

Senior Software Developer | Development Support Lead Product, Agility

# Japanese English

January 2020 - May 2021

- Served as a second developer on a system modernization project.
- Built the *app architecture and design* system components.
- Implemented workflows and guidelines for code consistency, readability, maintainability, and testability.
- **Conducted R&D** (research and development) for libraries and ways to improve our codebase.
- Helped and mentored junior developers from various backgrounds.

#### Software Engineer, Asolvi, Trondheim, Norway

June 2021 — April 2022

- *Collaborated* with stakeholders during development processes to confirm creative proposals and design best practices.
- Identified web-based user interactions and developed highly responsive reusable user interface components via React concepts.
- Troubleshot *interface software and debugged* application codes to improve functionality and optimal performance.
- Coordinated with *development team of 4* to discuss user interface ideas and applications.
- Translated designs & wireframes into high-quality code and wrote application interface code via JavaScript following React, Redux, Redux saga, Fire base workflows.
- Reviewed application requirements and interface designs to ensure compatibility with existing applications.

### **Education**

#### Bachelor of Science, The University of Tokyo, Tokyo, Japan

March 2012 - February 2016

- Operating Systems Architecture
- Usability in Website and Software Design
- C++Programming I & II
- Web Page Development Relational Database Design & SQL